# Rajavel Pachamuthu

rajavel@protonmail.com | Chennai, India | +91-95353 23478 | rajavel.me

#### **SUMMARY**

Certified Network Professional with over 13 years of experience in designing, deploying, and maintaining Network infrastructure for various Professional services companies and Telecom Service Providers. Extensive experience in Cisco Routing & Switching, Cloud Networking and SD-WAN implementations.

#### **SKILLS & TOOLS**

- Hardware: Cisco Catalyst 2960, 3650, 3850, 4500, 9000, Nexus 5K switches & Cisco ISRG2, ISR4K, CSR1000v, ASR1001-X routers and Palo Alto Firewalls.
- Protocols: TCP/IP, BGP, OSPF and EIGRP.
- SD-WAN: Versa & VeloCloud.
- Public Cloud: AWS and Azure Networking.
- Switching: STP, VTP, EtherChannel, vPC, Stacking and Layer 2 Security.
- Network Overlays & Services: GRE, IPsec, DMVPN, MPLS, QoS, IP SLA, HSRP, VRRP, NAT and EEM.
- Tools: Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE), Cisco Prime Infrastructure, Cisco APIC-EM server, SolarWinds, iPerf and Wireshark.
- Automation: Ansible.

#### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- CCNP-Enterprise Cisco Certified Network Professional Enterprise.
  - Cisco Certified Specialist Enterprise Design (CCS-ED)
  - Cisco Certified Specialist Enterprise Core (CCS-ECore)
  - o Cisco Certified Specialist Enterprise Advanced Infrastructure Implementation (CCS-EAII)
- AWS Certified Advanced Networking Specialty.
- CCNA Cisco Certified Network Associate

### **EMPLOYMENT**

Tata Communications Limited, Chennai, India Manager – SDWAN Engineering October 2020 – Present

- Design and implement Versa SD-WAN solutions for dedicated and multi-tenant deployments.
- Provide technical demonstrations and use cases of the system to customers.
- Validate new features and solution requirements from customers and create Standard Operating Procedure documents for Implementation and Support teams.
- Analyze customer solicitations (RFIs, RFPs, etc.), requirements and design solution proposals.
- Acting as technical lead in cooperation with presales and project management teams.

- Installed & supported network infrastructure of a Danish Manufacturing company of 300+ branch locations.
- Completed the migration branch locations to VeloCloud SDWAN from DMVPN solution.
- Played key role in Cloud readiness project and set up connectivity between Azure and On-Premises datacenters & branch sites.
- Configured & supported Routers, Catalyst and Nexus Switches, Network Access control solutions, Firewalls, QoS and Tunneling technologies.
- Designed and deployed new branch locations with coordination of Client's local IT technicians.
- Provided and implemented technical solutions for the Client requests and new projects.
- Involved in various POCs (Proof of Concept) to test drive new products and technologies.

Sify Technologies Ltd., Chennai, India Global NOC Engineer

November 2011 – July 2013

- Implemented and supported multiple circuits like MPLS VPN and Internet links for customers.
- Performed key role in integrating all the private and public sector banks under state owned IDRBT MPLS VPN network.
- Migrated 300+ branch locations of a large private bank to MPLS network with end-to-end QoS.
- Configured and maintained VPNs in Fortinet Firewall, Juniper SSG and Client end devices.
- Provided technical solutions and implemented new requirements for Managed Customers.
- Carried out Change Management activities for customers' network.

Firstsource Solutions Ltd., Chennai, India Junior NOC Engineer September 2010 – November 2011

- Provided level one support for IPLC, MPLS and Internet circuits, and worked closely with telecom providers to debug and diagnose network and circuit problems.
- Monitored over 3000 Nodes which includes Network devices and Servers through various tools like HP open view NNM, ManageEngine OpManager, IT360, CLI Manager and Netflow Analyzer.

Allnet Systems Pvt. Ltd., Chennai, India Network Engineer July 2009 – September 2010

- Installed and configured network devices, including routers, modems, hubs and switches.
- Provided network and VoIP support for 20+ different client networks.

## **EDUCATION**

Anna University, Chennai, India Bachelor of Engineering (Electronics & Communication Engineering) August 2005 - April 2009